Re: Cover Letter and Resume – Programmer Python Web SAS - Data Science – Robotics

Dear Hiring Manager,

Creativity rarely fits the mold, fails a lot before success, requires curiosity, imagination, uniqueness, intelligence, motivation, persistence, teamwork, diligence, and accountability to record and act on unexpected moments of insight and genius. Thomas Edison proved that persistence is a key factor to success with 1,000 failed attempts before he created the first light bulb. What do I have in common with Thomas Edison, Alan Alda, Bill Gates, Guido van Rossum (Python), and Bill and Bob Meistrell (Inventor of Body Glove wet suit)? Read my Introduction/Bio written for Thomas Edison State University. A one-page interesting, good read (https://github.com/JohnMeistrell/MA/wiki).

As I am enrolled at Thomas State University for bachelor's degree in data science, PLA, with 4.0 GPA with target graduation 2024, my original goal of 2023 was delayed after hospitalization in December 2022 for COVID-19 followed by lengthy recovery. Fortunately, I am back to full health and eagerly pursuing my passion for data science, statistics, and new career using the creativity success factors, my Clinical Medical Assistant and computer technical experience with my high IQ and on the right team to achieve my goal to improve people's health and lives.

Having an IQ of 127 for concepts and cognitive ability, professionally determined in 2022 using the Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale- Fourth Edition (WAIS – IV), combined with my experience and uniqueness is an asset to all. I learn in reverse to understand the whys before the technical how's.

We share common core values, curiosity, passion, accountability, and inspiration, and exploration with an embrace of technology to create solutions and solve problems to make many lives better. I look forward to hearing from you, and I am available for an interview at your convenience.

Sincerely,

John Meistrell

128 Schooner Avenue, Barnegat, NJ 08005 908-235-7304 J.MeistrellMA@gmail.com

John Meistress

JOHN MEISTRELL

Portfolio: www.github.com/JohnMeistrell/MA/wiki BARNEGAT, NJ (908) 235-7304 J.MEISTRELLMA@GMAIL.COM

Programmer Developer (Clinical, SAS, Python, Web), Technical Support Statistical Analyst, Data Miner, Data Science, and Robotics Creator.

- Driven and motivated individual continuously learning with ambitions for a Data Scientist, Architect, or Engineer.
- Excellent IT troubleshooting and repairing abilities.
- Skilled in databases, SQL and in technology, SAS, Python with R rpy2, C#, Node.js, TypeScript, React, Web, Visual Studio IDE, Microsoft Office, Notepad++, GitHub, Juniper, networks, REXX, and macros.
- Setup hardware, software, new computers, installations, tools, and release management.
- Exercised and analyzed a wide range of real-life statistical scenarios in SAS OnDemand for a true understanding.
- Concepts and cognitive ability IQ of 127 using Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale (WAIS IV). Learned the whys first.
- Portfolio/Wiki Natural curiosity, Data Science, Statistics, Karaoke Web App (React, jQuery, and ES6), and more.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Thomas Edison State University, Trenton, NJ

05/2024

Bachelor of Science in Data Science and Analytics – Current GPA 4.0

Ocean County College, Toms River, NJ

09/2020

Certified Clinical Medical Assistant Certificate

Raritan Valley Community College, Branchburg Township, NJ

05/2014

Pharmacy Technician Certificate

National Healthcare Association NHA and American Heart Association AHA

- Certified Clinical Medical Assistant, (CCMA) 06/2024
- Certified Basic Life Support, (BLS)

exp:10/2023

- Certified EKG Technician, (CET)
- exp:07/2024
- Certified Phlebotomy Technician, (CPT) exp:08/2024

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance/Tutor, Sole Proprietor, Barnegat, NJ

06/2022 - Present

Tutored math, statistics, Web development, troubleshooting, research methods, and more.

Clinical Operations Specialist, Rothman Orthopedics, Manahawkin, NJ

Summer position 2021

- Entered patient vitals, chief complaints, medication & medical history into Electronic Medical Record (EMR).
- Assisted during medical examinations. Prepared and cleaned treatment rooms and medical instruments.

IT Support Technician, Chubb Insurance - Township of Warren, NJ

School Bus Driver, Barnegat Board of Education, Barnegat, NJ

7/1999 - 10/2010

- Provided status updates to multiple levels of management through various communication means.
- Diagnosed and updated software while completing quick fix tickets and followed up to ensure satisfaction.
- Responded to technical emergencies outside of regular office hours on an as needed basis.

Produced applications with a variety of technical languages including REXX and VB.NET.

12/2018 - Present

- Utilize clear communication, strong interpersonal skills, empathy, and conflict resolution skills to manage, defuse, prevent, and address a range of student conduct concerns, as well as emotionally charged parents.
- Safely transport students and rapidly adjust to dynamically changing road conditions.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Adept troubleshooting skills. Hardware and software proficiency.
- Proficient in web research, Microsoft Office, Word, Excel, Outlook, and PowerPoint.
- Strong knowledge in EMR, Navient Medical Billing, NJMMIS, medical billing, and coding.